Preliminary Inventory to the Bernard and Jewel Bellush Papers WAG.030
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VII: Unprocessed Files, 1940s-2000.
  - Nearing, Scott, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Communist Party U.S.A., 1973-1979 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Populism, Undated (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Populism, Undated (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - WWI: Civil Liberties, 1960-1973 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Socialist Party U.S.A., Undated (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - New Deal: Socialist Party, Undated (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Old/New Left, 1972-1982 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - New Left, Undated (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Socialism and Populism, Undated (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Debs, Eugene V., Undated (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - Socialist Party, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Old/New Deal Views, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Roosevelt Presidency, Response to, Undated (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - WWII and McCarthyism, Undated (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - The Divided Left, Undated (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Hillquit, Morris, Undated (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - Socialism and the "Negro", 1970 (Box 15, Folder 50)
  - Socialist Party, Undated (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - Marxist Tradition in U.S.A., Undated (Box 15, Folder 52)
  - World Veterans Federation (on Kosovo), 1999 (Box 15, Folder 53)
  - Great Neck Vote, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Elections (Nassau County), 1980 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Peabody, Endicott, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Petra, Jordan, Trip to, Nov 1998 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Blank, Blanche "Degrees: Who Need Them?", 1972 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Oct 2007-Dec 2001 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - To Do/To Read, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1990s (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Holland, Letter from, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Holland Memoir, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Moslem Review, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - NYC-ADA, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - NY State Coordinating Council, 1986-1987 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - NYS-ADA, 1986-1987 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - NY ADA: Removal of Roskoff, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - NY ADA: Election Results, etc., 1982 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Goodman, Myra and Lee Dana, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Universal Utilities, 1981-1984 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Hankin, Joe, 1985-1988 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Jewish Students and the Left, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, Jun 1994-Sep 1994 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Cultural Radicals, 1934, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - McCarthy, Thaddeus, 1980-1982 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Kreinder Family, 1984-1988 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Lamarche, Gary and Ellen Chuse, 1978-1987 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Union Power and New York: Victor Gotbaum and District Council 37: Reviews, 1985-1986 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - ADA: Nominating Committee, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - NGO: Memo of Understanding, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - AFC-ACLU, 1983-1984 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Book Reviews, 1961-1977 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Behrens, Rose, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Feingold, Stan, 1978-1979 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Blaesser, Bill and Helen, 1978-1979 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, Jun 2000-Sep 2000 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Fund for New Priorities in America, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence, Feb 2000-May 2000 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Gordon, Murray, 1985-1987 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Gorbachev letter, Reaction to, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Auschwitz: Anti-Semitism in Europe and U.S., 1970s (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Blacks and Jews, 1973-1975 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, Jun 2007-Oct 2001 (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - JFK and LBJ: Social Commentary, Undated (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Black Leadership and Changes, 1970s (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - ADA: National Board, 1995-1996 (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - Goodlich, Michael, 1984-1993 (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - District Council 37: Clippings, 1996-1998 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - DC 37, Undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - ADA, Long Island Resolution, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Goodman, Barrie and Lee D., 1996 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Goodman, Lee (Memorial), 1996 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - ADA Correspondence, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - ADA, Long Island Executive Committee, Sep 1998 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - ADA, Long Island Executive Committee, May 1998 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - ADA, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Berger, Henry and Irene Jillson, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - ADA Constitution, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - City College of New York Syllabi (History Class), Undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Socialism: Amalgamated Housing, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Gus Tyler Birthday, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Uhler, Kathie, Undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - ADA, Long Island New Release on Milosevic, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Union for Democracy Action, 1947-1954 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Partner in Education Certificate, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - CCNY Commencement Exercise Program, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - American Radicalism, 1997-1998 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Bellush Family, 1993-1999 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Bellush, Debbi, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Mom Bellush, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Bellush, Debbi, 1990-1994 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Bellush, Debbi, 1997-1998 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Bellush, Jewel, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - 80th Birthday / 50th Anniversary, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Bellush, Debbi, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - CCNY, Retirement from, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Pension forms, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Bellush, Jewel: Pension, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Bellush, Jewel: Retirement, 1974-1980 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Pension File, 1970-1977 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: Retirement/Pension, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Bellush-Goldberg Families, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Bellush, Irv, 1985-1987 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Misc. Periodicals/Serials, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - ADA, Long Island, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D.: Reviews as Governor, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Radicalism: Definition and Description, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - New Left, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Danish Socialism and the Kansas Prairie, Undated (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Socialist Administration 1927-1931, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - New Left, 1968-1971 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - The South in the Saddle: Racial Politics During the Wilson Years, Undated (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - The Communist Party of the 1930s and the New Left, Undated (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - Revisionists, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - IWWW: "One Big Union", 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - WWI Antimilitarism and Antiradicalism, 1971-1976 (Box 16, Folder 50)
  - New York State Politics Program 1893-1910, Undated (Box 16, Folder 51)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, Undated (Box 16, Folder 52)
  - New Deal and the Blacks (Articles), 1969 (Box 16, Folder 53)
  - Communists and Miners: 1928-1933, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence, 1980s (Box 16, Folder 55)
  - Manuscript: "David Dubinsky and the Labor Wars", 2002 (Box 16, Folder 56)
  - Video: Interview with Bernard Bellush, Nov 1999 (Box 16, Folder 57)
  - Yearbook: Harford Junior College, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Women in the Abolition Movement 1830-1869 by Bellush, Jewel, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Herbert H. Lehman as Governor: Case Studies in Legislative Leadership by Bellush, Jewel, Undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Antioch Bookplates, Undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Yearbook: CUNY, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Civil Rights Audit of the National Guard, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Center for U.N. reform Education: Board of Trustees Meeting, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Family Clippings, Undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - ADA: Income and Inequality, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - U.S. Agriculture, Corruption of, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - John Monroe High School (Misc.), 1936 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Passports (6), Undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Yearbook: James Monroe High School, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Yearbook: Lexicon, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Giftbook: Bellush 75th Birthday, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Tape: ADA Roosevelt Day Dinner, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Tape: Naum Ross Interview, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Tape: Handler, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Yearbook: CCNY, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - AVC: Affairs Commission, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Beder, Bernie, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Croatia: Gubic, Marijan, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - DC 37: Review of "Union Power" by Herman Benson, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - DC 37 Talk, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - American Radicalism, Undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - DC 37 Clippings, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Municipal Unions in Crisis, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Erabrink, Gerard and Nelly, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - A Union Saves the City, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Poland-Midrasz, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Dr. McKinley, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Wallenberg Case, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - CCNY: Faculty Senate 25th Anniversary, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Christian Identity Movement, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Christensen, Lilly K., 1988 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Dubinsky and the Communist Party, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Lower East Side Tenement Museum, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - East Europe Trip, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Farrakhan, Louis quotes, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Feingold, Stan, 1996-1997 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Ostroff, Frieda, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Freedman, Monroe, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Students, Letters from, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Israel, Fred, 1984-1986 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Hankin, Joe, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Hoffman, Manuela, Undated (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Holocaust/FDR Library, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - IRS, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Israel Articles, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Histadrut: General Federation of Labour in Israel, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Kessler, Eve (Forward), 1977 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Kibbutz, Yiftah, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Labor: USA, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Land Mines and Disarmament, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Levy, Uriah Phillips, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - New Deal: Civilian Conservation Corps., 1992 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Michel-Shaehar, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Pacemaker Implant, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Peabody, Endicott "Chub", 1996 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Regulski, Jerzy, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Reuther, Elisabeth, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Reuther, Walter and May, Undated (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - Stoler, Mark: Israel, 1984-1994 (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - Tax Info for Sep. Debate, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Tellegen, Egbert: Telegrams, 1979, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - Tyler, Gus: Retirement Speech, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 47)
  - Unemployment, Undated (Box 18, Folder 48)
  - Vita, Undated (Box 18, Folder 49)
  - Weinstein, Jack and Evelyn, 1978-1980 (Box 18, Folder 50)
  - Welfare Reform, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 51)
  - World Veterans Federation, 1990-1997 (Box 18, Folder 52)
  - ADA: Humphrey-Roosevelt Day Dinner Remarks, Undated (Box 18, Folder 53)
  - Israeli Article, Responses to, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 54)
  - ADA National Board Meeting, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 55)
  - ADA Long Island: on Terrorism, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 56)
  - ADA Long Island Executive Committee Meeting, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 57)
  - ADA and Steve Israel, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 58)
  - ADA Long Island, 2000-2001 (Box 18, Folder 59)
  - Affirmative Action: Colleges, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 60)
  - American Jewish Committee, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 61)
  - Arbel, Odie, 1998-1999 (Box 18, Folder 62)
  - Ashkenazy, Tal, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 63)
  - American Veterans Committee, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 64)
  - AVC, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 65)
  - Arital, Collette (Israel), 1999 (Box 18, Folder 66)
  - ABC Tours: Sicily, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 67)
  - Kosovo: ADA Resolution, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 68)
  - Academic Freedom: ACLU (American Civil Liberties Union), 1966 (Box 18, Folder 69)
  - ADA Long island, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 70)
  - ADA: Chapter Effectiveness Committee, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 71)
  - ADA: Convention Planning Committee, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 72)
  - ADA Long Island: Names and Addresses, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 73)
  - National Board Meeting Corrections, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 74)
  - ADA: NEC, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 75)
  - ADA: Letter to Jontz, Jim, Bill Markus, and Amy Isaacs, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 76)
  - ADA Long Island Mailing, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 77)
  - Bedouins and other Organizations, 1994-1999 (Box 18, Folder 78)
  - Ben Uri Museum: London, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 79)
  - Beretz, Hal, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 80)
  - Bisogono, Tony, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 81)
  - Brandeis: President Reinharz, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 82)
  - Brasz, Henk, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 83)
  - Brasz, Ineke, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 84)
  - Bronx Community College: Testimony re: Student Take-Over, Undated (Box 18, Folder 85)
  - Carpeting, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 86)
  - Carroll, Paul and Rachel, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 87)
  - CCNY: History Department, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 88)
  - CCNY: 60th Reunion (1941), 2001 (Box 18, Folder 89)
  - CCNY: Invitation List, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 90)
  - Clinton Administration, 1993-1996 (Box 18, Folder 91)
  - Dr. Cohen, David: NYU Medical, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 92)
  - Center for U.N. Reform Education (CURE), 2001 (Box 18, Folder 93)
  - Dr. Cooper: Letter re: Surgery, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 94)
  - DC 37, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 95)
  - Debs, Eugene V., 1999 (Box 18, Folder 96)
  - Dubrovnik, Undated (Box 18, Folder 97)
  - Elder Hostel: London, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 98)
  - FDR, the Jews and the Holocaust, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 99)
  - FDR, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 100)
  - Feingold, Stanley, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 101)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1980 (Box 18, Folder 102)
  - Tyler Articles, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 103)
  - Prospects for Peace, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 104)
  - Jews and FDR, 1983-1984 (Box 18, Folder 105)
  - CCNY: Instructors Handbook, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - DPI/NGO Conference, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - It Takes Two to Tango: Dr. Blanche Blank, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - International Conference: Social Democracy, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - FDR and Jews: Articles, Undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Forward Articles, 1994-1997 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Small Arms Disarmament Daily, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Politics (Vermont): Sanders, Bernie, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Sanders, Bernie (Vermont), 1999 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Jews in New England, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Woodstock and Hanover Jewish Communities, 1992-1997 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Woodstock and Hanover Jewish Communities, 1993-1995 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Jews in the Upper Valley, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Sanders, Bernie, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Sanders, Bernie, 1990-1992 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Veterans Unit: Articles, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Sample Essays, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Veterans: Background Documents, Undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - College Newspapers, 1940s (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Commission on State-City Relations, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Commission on State-City Relations, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - 616th Ordnance Ammunition Company: WWII, Undated (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - The Living History Project Final Report, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Senate: Retirement Remarks, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - City University Committee on Enrollment Policies, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - 1984 Election Results, Analysis, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Jun 1993-Sep 1993 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Jun 1995-Sep 1995 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Sep 1993-Oct 1993 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1993-Apr 1993 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Israel, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Roosevelt, N.J., 1992-1993 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Jan 2007-Mar 2001 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1979-Jun 1979 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1980-May 1980 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Feb 1982 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Brown, Theresa, 1980-1981 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Jun 1975-Dec 1975 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Judicial Conference: Victor Gotbaum, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Victor Gotbaum vs. Wurf, 1978-1979 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Victor Gotbaum: Correspondence, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Victor Gotbaum: Correspondence, 1975-1979 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Victor Gotbaum: Speeches, Articles, 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Victor Gotbaum: White House Fellows and Misc., 1970s-1980s (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, Undated (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Corruption in DC 37?, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Victor Gotbaum and OCB, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 26)